Guide to the Bette S. Garber Photographs
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Bette S. Garber photographs
1970-1983
GEN MSS 756
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.5
(2 boxes)
Garber, Bette S.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from John Waite Rare Books on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2010.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Bette S. Garber
Bette S. Garber (1942-2008) was an American photographer known for documenting tractor-trailer trucks, truck drivers, and the culture of long-haul trucking in the United States. She wrote and photographed for industry journals, magazines, and newsletters, such as Trucker News, American Trucker, and others. She also published four photo books, Custom Semi Trucks (2003), Custom Semi (2005), Custom Semi Trucks 2 (2006), and Ultra-Custom Semi Trucks (2008).
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of black and white photographs, color photographs, contact sheets, negatives, and a photograph album, with related printed material. The photographs document scenes of American long-haul trucking, trucks, and truck drivers.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged in a very rough alphabetical order, maintaining the order in which they were received.
Truck drivers -- United States; Truck driving -- United States; Photograph albums; Photographic prints; Garber, Bette S.
- Livestock Trucking and Bonneville Salt Flats Speed Records, correspondence and photographs, undated (Box 1)
- Diesel Drag Races, York Raceway, York, Pennsylvania - photograph album, 1976 September 12; 2 (Box 1)
  Arrangement
  The photographic contents of the Diesel Drag Races album have been removed due to preservation concerns. The contents are located within the second folder.
- Diners and truckstops, undated (Box 1)
- "Foxes and the Hounds" - Scales, ports of entry, highway checks, cops, undated (Box 1)
- Hagerstown, Mayland, 1983 May 6-7 (Box 1)
- Hunts Point, undated (Box 1)
- ITA Convention, 1978 (Box 1)
- ITA Meeting - 2 photographs, undated (Box 1)
- Leaders - Prominence, undated (Box 1)
- Louisiana and miscellaneous negatives, undated (Box 1)
- Michael, undated (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous pictures and junk, 1970s (Box 1)
- Negatives, undated (Box 1)
- Negatives, 1970s (Box 1)
- Negatives and contactt prints, undated (Box 1)
- Night, undated (Box 1)
- Night and miscellaneous pictures and negatives, undated (Box 1)
- Photocopies and negatives, undated (Box 1)
- Protests, undated (Box 1)
- Steel-Haulers' Strike photographs and clippings, 1978 December (Box 1)
- Tanker and miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
- Tearsheets from MTN, correspondence and clippings, undated (Box 1)
- Traffic jams, photographs, undated (Box 1)
- Truckers miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
- Women truckers, undated (Box 1)
- 4x6 black and white photographs, undated; 5 (Box 2)
- 5x7 black and white photographs [empty folder], undated (Box 2)
- Various black and white photographs, undated; 2 (Box 2)
- Various color photographs, undated (Box 2)